Speaker 1: Senator Hawley of Missouri.
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): Thank you very much, Mr. Chairman. Judge, congratulations on your nomination. It's nice to see you again. Congratulations to all of your family. I know that this is a big moment for you and for them, and rightly so. I enjoyed our meeting a couple of weeks ago. You know, as I've said to folks who've asked about it, one of the things I particularly appreciated about our meeting, besides how much time you gave me, was how candid and forthcoming you were, which I really respected. And I look forward to a candid conversation
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): Again, in the days that come, and by the way, I'm admiring how you're sitting so
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): stoically through all of this, all this Senator talk. But I'm looking forward to visiting with you again. You did me the honor when we sat down of being very candid, and I hope I was candid with you. I've been candid since. I want to be candid with you
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): today so you know exactly what it is I want to talk about. And so you know exactly where my head is at. So let me say,
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): a few things that I'm concerned about. Aspects of your record that trouble
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): me. This will come as no surprise. I've said it in public already. But I want to be, again, very candid in the interest
of an
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): open and honest discussion and specifics. So here are, I hope, in the next couple of days, some of the cases from your time on
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): the court, the district court, the federal district court, that I hope that we can talk about. Let me just run through a few of them so you know exactly which ones I mean. United States versus Hawkins.
This
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): was a child pornography case where the defendant distributed multiple images of child porn, possessed dozens more, including videos. The federal
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): sentencing guidelines recommended a sentence of 97 to 121 months in
prison.
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): Prosecutors recommended 24 months in prison. Judge Jackson gave the defendant three months in prison. United States versus Chazin, that case, the defendant possessed 48 files of child pornography,
The
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): federal guidelines recommended 78 to 97
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): months in prison. The prosecutor recommended the same. Judge Jackson sentenced him to 28 months. United
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): States versus Cooper. There the defendant possessed dozens of images of child pornography and distributed, I should say distributed, dozens of
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): images of child pornography, possessed over 600.
The
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): federal guidelines recommended 151 to 188 months in prison. That's a long time. The prosecutor recommended 72 months. Judge Jackson gave
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): the defendant 60 months, which was the lowest sentence permitted by the law.
United States v.
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): Down, that's a case where the defendant distributed 33 graphic images and videos of child sexual assault to an anonymous messaging app, unfortunately a practice that's becoming more common. The
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): federal guidelines recommended 70 to 87 months in prison.
The
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): prosecutor recommended 70 months in prison. Judge Jackson sentenced him to only 60 months. Again, that's the lowest level that was permitted
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): by law in that case. United States v. Stewart. The defendant there distributed scores of images of children suffering sexual abuse. The guidelines recommended 97 to 121 months in prison. The prosecutor recommended 97 months in prison. Judge Jackson gave him 57 months.
In the
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): United States v. Sears, the defendant distributed over
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): 100 videos of child pornography.
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): The guidelines recommended
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): 97 to 121 months in prison. The prosecutor recommended 97 months
in prison.
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): Judge Jackson gave him 71 months.
In the
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): United States v. Savage, the defendant was
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): convicted of traveling across state lines to engage in sexual intercourse with a child and also possessed six separate thumb drives of child pornography
The
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): guidelines recommended 46 to 57 months in prison. The prosecutor recommended 49 months in prison. Judge Jackson sentenced him to 37 months in prison. Now those
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): are seven
cases that
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): represent as near as we can tell all of Judge Jackson's cases dealing with child pornography from her time on the district court in which she had some discretion to hand down a sentence. There's some other cases in which
the law she
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): didn't have any discretion. The law bound the sentence that she had to had to give,
and what concerns me
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): and I've been very candid about this, is that in every
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): case, in each of these seven, Judge Jackson handed down a lenient sentence that was below what the federal guidelines recommended and below what prosecutors requested.
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): And so I think there's a lot to talk about there and I look forward to talking about it. Now I will note that some
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): have said that the federal sentencing guidelines are too harsh on child sex crimes, especially child pornography. I've heard that argument a lot in recent days. The chairman quoted
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): someone earlier today who takes that point of view. I'll just be honest, I can't say that I agree with that.
I mean,
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): the amount of child pornography in circulation has absolutely exploded in recent years. Here's a New York Times report from 2019. I'm quoting now. Last year, tech companies reported over 45 million online photos and videos of children being sexually abused, more than double
what they
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): found the previous year. The report goes on to say this.
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): 20 years ago, these online images were a problem.
10 years
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): ago, they were an epidemic.
Now the
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): crisis is at a breaking point. Unfortunately, it's even worse than that. Just last week, the National Center for Missing and Exploited
Children reported
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): finding 85 million files of child pornography in 2021. And of course, this committee has heard testimony
from
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): prosecutors and others who are grappling with the problem of how to get at this porn and those who distribute it, how to prosecute them and hold them accountable. Here's my point: I think it's difficult against this backdrop to argue that the sentencing guidelines are too harsh or outmoded or that we should be somehow treating child porn offenders more leniently
than
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): the guidelines recommend.
But I
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): wanna be clear
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): about this, but those arguments that I've just been rehearsing, those who say that, that's not what Judge Jackson has said. She hasn't had the chance yet to respond to this and she deserves that chance. So others have made these arguments. I don't agree with them, but I think it's important we hear from Judge Jackson and we'll have the chance to in coming days.
And I
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): think again, the candor that Judge Jackson has shown previously, I look forward to, and she deserves the ability to speak for herself on this issue.
So, I
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): will just say, in closing, Mr. Chairman, some have asked
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): why did I raise these questions ahead of the hearing? Why not wait until the hearing and spring them on Judge Jackson as it were? And my answer
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): to that is very simple. I'm not interested in trapping Judge Jackson. I'm not interested in trying to play gotcha. I'm interested in her answers. Because
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): I found in our time together that she was enormously thoughtful, enormously accomplished.
Speaker 3 (lower-pitched voice): And I suspect has a coherent view, an explanation, and a set of
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): thinking, way of thinking about this that I look forward to hearing.
And I
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): think she deserves the chance to talk about it. I think the American people deserve the chance to hear her answers.
So they're my
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): concerns, Judge. They're the cases I imagine there'll be others that we can talk about on other subjects, but I'd like to talk about those so you know exactly where I'm coming from. Thanks again for giving me the time a few weeks ago. Congratulations again. I look forward to finally hearing from you tomorrow. Thank you, Mr. Chairman.